<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:space="preserve" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Template mining for the extraction of citation from digital documents</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Division of Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Nanyang Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>639798</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gobinda</forename><surname>Chowdhury</surname></persName>
							<email>asggchowdhury@ntu.edu.sg</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Division of Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Nanyang Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>639798</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Schubert</forename><surname>Foo</surname></persName>
							<email>assfoo@ntu.edu.sg</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Applied Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Division of Information Studies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Nanyang Technological University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Nanyang Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>639798</postCode>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Template mining for the extraction of citation from digital documents</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">66534D75AC960731C54FF91BE5004B8A</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2" ident="GROBID" when="2025-10-22T03:06+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<label type="revision">a91ee48</label>
					<label type="parameters">startPage=-1, endPage=-1, consolidateCitations=0, consolidateHeader=0, consolidateFunders=0, includeRawAffiliations=false, includeRawCitations=false, includeRawCopyrights=false, generateTeiIds=false, generateTeiCoordinates=[], sentenceSegmentation=false, flavor=null</label>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>template mining</term>
					<term>cited article</term>
					<term>citing article</term>
					<term>information extraction</term>
					<term>citation database</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In order to exploit the rapid growth of digital documents in the Internet, there is an urgent need to efficiently determine and extract relevant information from these documents. This study discusses an approach to extracting citation information from digital documents. Four templates are produced by using template mining techniques, one for extracting information from citing articles and the other three for extraction information from cited articles (citations). These are subsequently applied to the chosen domain of Library and Information Science (LIS). The sublanguages of citations are examined, and the flowcharts of the four templates are described in detail. This study further describes the evaluation that was carried out manually, the results obtained and the limitations of this study.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>events in driving the field of IR forward <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. The detailed review, dividing the IE researches into three groups: early work on template filing, the message understanding conferences (MUCs), and other works on information extraction, has been provided by Gaizauskas and Wilks <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Template mining is a particular technique used in IE. The NLP technique of template mining can be used to extract data directly from text if either the data and/or the text surrounding the data form recognizable patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. When text matches a template, the system extracts data according to instructions associated with that template. Data extraction using data mining had long been dismissed by the NLP community because of its narrow domain specificity. Areas in which template mining has been successfully applied include the extraction of proper names by Cowie and Lehnert <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>; extraction of facts from press releases related to company and financial information in systems like ARTANS <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, SCISOR <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, JASPER <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, LOLITA <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> and FIES <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>; abstracting scientific papers by Jones and Paice <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>; summarizing new product information by Shuldberg et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>; extraction of data from analytical chemistry papers by Postma et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref> and Postma &amp; Kateman <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>; extraction of reaction information from experimental sections of papers in the chemistry journals by Zamora and Blower <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>; processing of generic and specific chemical designations from chemical patents by Chowdhur y and Lynch <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref> and Kemp <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>; and extraction of bibliographic citations from full texts of patents by Lawson et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Citation Analysis and Template Mining</head><p>The problem with citation analysis in the digital age is to find a collection of Web pages or ejournals and print journal articles that are tightly enough linked, so that there is something to measure <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. The use of citation data to locate newer works that cite important prior works in a field has long been an important technique for literature research. Unfortunately, the available indexes (e.g. SCI and SSCI) tend to be quite limited in their coverage, indexing only selected sets of print academic journals without including e-journals and Web pages. Cameron <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> called for a universal, Internet-based, bibliographic and citation database which would link every scholarly work ever written -no matter how published -to every work that it cites and every work that cites it. Such a database could revolutionize many aspects of scholarly communication: literature research, keeping current with new literature, evaluation of scholarly work, choice of publication venue, improvement of information retrieval and so on. Once the universal or semiuniversal citation databases have been established automatically, bibliometric research, webmetric research will be the next era of research activities. Chowdhury <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> has mentioned that template mining can be used to develop citation databases automatically and such databases may contain information something similar to the ISI databases, such as the journal information about the citing article, author name, author address, title, abstract, keywords, as well as author, journal, title and bibliographic details of the cited articles. Lawson et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> have used template mining to extract citation information from the full text of chemical patents.</p><p>Harter <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref> conducted a Webmetrics study with 39 scholarly journals that began electronic publication no later than 1993. This study identified the eight most highly cited e-journals. Citation and publication data for three high ranking e-journals in the study were compared to similar data for print journals in the same fields. The seven most highly cited articles from the ejournals in the study were determined.</p><p>Recently, several systems have been developed for reference links from online journal articles to other journal articles. Caplan &amp; Arms <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> summarized the current state-of-the-art of reference linking for online journal articles. Some of the reference linking systems include: NASA Astrophysics Data System (ADS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, National Library of Medicine's PubMed/PubRef (PubMed) system <ref type="bibr">[26]</ref>, and ISI's web of science <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[27]</ref>.</p><p>This study hypothesizes that the template mining technique can be used to extract citation information from printed and digital full-text articles so that we can establish these universal or semi-universal citation databases automatically before too long in the future. In order to prove this hypothesis, an experiment was conducted with some selected electronic journal articles, and the initial results have been quite promising. This paper provide details of this experiment and suggests some measures to be taken by the publishers and authors of electronic document in order to facilitate template mining techniques.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methodology</head><p>The journals in this study were chosen based on the following selection criteria: (1) peerreviewed/refereed; (2) research-oriented; (3) Full coverage of the year 1998, and (4) subject domain in LIS. Six parallel publishing journals (i.e. those journals that have both printed and electronic versions) and six pure e-journals (those that are only available in electronic forms) were chosen as the research samples. Only research-oriented journal articles were considered for investigation, since they usually have citation data. Footnotes and endnotes were excluded from this study because very small number of articles with footnotes have appeared in this study. One article was selected randomly from each issue of 1998 among these 12 journals. Totally, 77 articles were selected which contain 2,179 citations. These 77 articles were separated into two sets, one (43 articles with 1,067 citations) for creating the templates and the other one (34 articles with 1,112 citations) for testing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Templates</head><p>The objective of this study was to extract citation information (both the citing and cited references) from the digital documents. In order to create appropriate templates for this template mining study an iterative process of template specification, evaluation and modification was performed. The derivation of the templates is therefore the result of a thorough analysis of the articles selected by identifying the list of patterns associated with these articles. It is assumed that these patterns are representative of other journal collections, provided that they follow some citation patterns strictly. Experience shows that citation patterns are followed strictly in printed journals, and in fact, each printed journal has a 'house style' for citation, and authors are required to follow that, and this also goes through editorial checking and correction. However, such standards/house styles, and strict adherence to those, are not common in electronic journals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Citing Article Template</head><p>From each article, information on the following items was to be gathered: source journal name, volume, issue, date of publication, ISSN, title, author name, author address, author email, keywords, abstract, acknowledgment, references, about the author, and so on. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> and Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref> shows the flowchart of the Citing Article Template.</p><p>Table 1. Tokens or cue information in citing article template INFORMATI ON UNIT CUE INFORMATION (TOKENS) PUNCTUATIONS Journal Information (one line or several lines) 'Vol.', 'Volume', 'Issue', 'No.', 'no.' d, d(d), 'ISSN', 'pp.', d-d;</p><p>resulted in the identification of 'cue information' preceding, within or following the templates as shown in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>.</p><p>The formats of data elements can vary significantly. For example, author and address's position in the citing articles and even author name and address show a great deal of variations (Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>); so do journal information, keywords, abstract, acknowledgments, references and so on. All these add complexity of deriving the citing article templates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>General Cited Article Templates</head><p>Examination of the references indicated that there are different ways to identify the different parts of references as shown in Table <ref type="table">2</ref>:</p><p>• Author name . Although author names have several variations, they have some fixed patterns.</p><p>In our study, we found two patterns for cited author name, one is author surname first, and the other one is the author forename first.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Figure 1. Flowchart of Citing Article Template</head><p>General Citing template Start journal info (Vol, Volume, ISSN, time) Call for journal template Title (line break+blank line) Author Forename(a,c.,c.(c. ) Author Surname (string between space and return/ and/,) a+return/ a+and/a+, Yes and/,/&amp;/Email (@) Email Yes Email address (university, country ) Author address Yes NO author name (a+ +a+(and/,)/c.(c.)+ +a+(and/,) Yes NO NO YES and/,/&amp; NO Email (@) Email address Yes keywords/ journal info NO Keywords (a;/,+a;/ ,+a;/,...) Yes Keywords Abstract(s)/Type of Article/para/ para NO Abstract (before Introduction, Background, Content) Yes info in footnote of page1(vol, ISSN, no, number, time, pp.) Call for journal template Yes NO Yes NO Call for journal template keywords Keywords Yes NO Yes Jour info Acknowledge/reference/about the author(authors) YES Acknowledge Yes About the author(authors) YES reference Acknowledgement (only extract name (including author, institute or university or funding name)) About the author(Author) (only extract author biography and address, email) Reference(s) (Bibliography, addtional readings, notes, references and further reading, Formal publications cited, Evolving Web pages cited) call for the reference templates journal info NO YES Call for journal template Yes End End NO NO Figure 2. Flowchart of Journal Template • Position of time . Time is easy to identify because they are four consecutive integers. But the positions of time in references are not so easy to track. It can appear at the beginning of the references (e.g. [Pinker 1994] Steven Pinker, The language instinct, New York: Harper Collins.), after the author name (e.g. Hjortgaard Christensen, F. and Ingwersen, P. (1996), "Online citation analyses: a methodological approach", Scientometrics, Vol. 37 No. 1, pp. 39-62.), at the end of the references (e.g. Mirjana Spasojevic and M. Satyanarayanan. An empirical study of a wide-area distributed file system. ACM Transactions on Computer Systems,14(2): 200-222, May 1996.) and so on. But we can use the four consecutive digits (especially it begins with 19, later on expanding to 20) as the token to identify the time no matter where it is. Journal name Vol/d Volume Yes no./(/No./ Issue/month Issue Yes time/date/pp./: Year Page NO time /date pp./: pp./:/d/ISSN Page time Year Yes ISSN ISSN pp./:/d ISSN NO time Year YES http (http:/ftp:) http address Yes NO NO Start Journal Template ,/line break NO Yes ISSN Yes NO NO • Title. Title can include article title, book title, journal title, conference title, report title and others.</p><p>The variety of titles makes extracting references by identifying titles unrealistic. Journal titles show almost as great a variation as book titles. However, some tokens and cue information hidden among them can help us to identify them, such as tokens like 'journal', 'proceedings', 'conference', 'report', 'technical report', 'in', '(ed.)', '(eds.)' and their abbreviations and so on. The cue information includes the punctuation, font style changing, publisher name and address, journal information (volume and page number) and so on. All these appear frequently in references and can be used as clues leading us to find the title information. Vinkler <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[28]</ref> observed that 55% of journal references come from only 10% of journal titles. Thus, a database containing the most frequently cited journals can be used to extract title. It also can help us decide whe ther the string is journal name in citing article template. In the same way, we also can build up conference database, publisher database, country database, university database, author name database, and so on, which can make it easier to distinguish different names.</p><p>More Authors Author1 Address1 Author2 Address2 ………… Author1 Author2 … Address1 Address2 … Author1 and/,/; Author2… Address AuthorN and/,/; AuthorM… Address Author1 Biography1+Address1 Author2 Biography2+Address2 ………… Author1 and/,/; Author2… Biography1 Biography2 …… Address1 Address2 Author1 and/,/; Author2 {} About the Author (biography and address) Author1 and/,/; Author2 … Address Author1 and/,/; Author2 … Figure 3 Variations for author and address ({} represents the text body) Table 2 Tokens or cue information in citing article template Figure 4. Flowchart of Cited Article Template 1 Author Surname ,/a+(/ (+time/ .+sen NO Yes ,/a+( Author Forename(a) &amp;/and/,/"/.+sen/ (+time NO YES and/&amp;/, Year in+author name+(Eds/ Ed/ed/eds)/in Book title or Proceedings title or others (report, proceedings, conference, symp) YES (+time/.+sen Journal name (journal name database/Vol, no, pp.) publisher/ time/http NO Address or Others : Publisher Name Yes Publisher Address NO http address (+pp./pp. Page Yes NO Title Title/Book/Report/ Conference Title(in, journal, report, proceedings, vol, no) Yes NO Yes J A:B/B,A Yes A:B Publisher Name YES B,A ,+a Publisher Address Yes time Time Yes NO NO (+pp./pp./http Page YES YES publisher NO time/http Year Yes time http/,+d/ pp./d-d Page Yes ,+d/pp./d-d YES http YES time/http YES http End ,+d/d/Vol./,+time Yes ,+d/d/Vol. Volume (+d/no./No./ ,/month Yes Issue(1/1-9) )+,/time Page(1/1-9) Yes Year )/)+,/:/pp./p./, /d-d/d/http Yes ,/)+,/:/)/pp./p./d-d/d Year(number only) ,+d/dd-dd/ http Web site address Yes http NO Page Yes ,+d/dd-dd http address YES http Journal name http YES time YES .+sen/"/(+time Yes NO NO "/,/./a/?/in NO Yes ./,/;/&lt;/char change YES NO YES ,+time Start Journal/Book/Conference/ Report/others ./,/;/?/&lt;/char chang Yes NO End NO NO Others NO End NO NO Cited Article Template 1 Book title or Proceedings title or others NO YES http YES Figure 5. Flowchart of Cited Article Te mplate 2 Author Forename a+,/a+and/ space/a+.+sen/ .+sen/"/,+sen/ time Yes a+,/a+and/a+.+sen/space Author Surname (a) and/,/.+sen/ "/,+sen/time NO YES if and/, YES if .+sen/ "/,+sen/tim e in+author+(Ed)/in Book title or Proceedings title or Others YES .+sen/"/,+sen/time Start [ Year(only number) Yes ] Yes NO Title Yes, title Title/Book/Report/Conference Title(in, journal, report, proceedings, vol, no) time/Publisher Year Publisher Address Yes Publisher : Publisher Name (including Inc.) Yes time(ignore month) Yes Other Address (non-http) NO http Yes http address pp./)+d/: Page Yes Journal Name ,+d/d/ vol(volume)/time Yes ,+d/d/vol(volume) Volume(1/1-9) (+d/(/d/no./No./ number/month Yes Issue Journal name/Report/ Conference Yes, J time/:/ pp./d-d Year Yes time NO Page Yes :/pp./d-d ,+time/(+time YES http pp./:/p./d-d Page Yes NO YES http http address Yes NO A:B/B,A YES A:B Publisher Name (including Inc.) YES B,A ,+a/ ,+time Publisher Address Yes ,+a YES time Yes ,+time NO http NO YES time Year Yes NO "/,/./a/?/in/char change NO Yes YES ./,/;/&lt;/char change ./,/;/&lt;/d/char change NO Yes End NO End NO NO Cited Article Template 2 Book or Proceedings title or Others NO Year YES time (cannot be month+year ) address YES YES No Yes NO NO NO NO NO NO NO Start http http address YES E-journal/Esource Name NO time Year YES End NO Cited Article Template 3 Figure 6. Flowchart of Cited Article Template 3 Citing article template 82% 84% 86% 88% 90% 92% 94% 96% 98% 100% Journal information Title Author name Author address Keywords Abstract Acknowledgement About the author Reference Percentage of extraction Figure 7 summarizes the results of evaluation for the Citing Article Template. Percentage of extraction is quite high in citing article template. The percentages of Reference, About the author, Acknowledgement and Journal Information are 100%</p><p>. This is so since all these parts of info rmation have fixed cue information to help the system locate them. For example, in identifying the Acknowledgement part, the system would just parse through the text to locate the token (i.e. sub heading) like 'Acknowledgement' or 'Acknowledgements', then all the information in this part will be completed for the acknowledgement slot. Thus, slots with fixed cue information or tokens will definitely have high extraction percentage.</p><p>Here title slot has the lowest extraction percentage because many articles ha ve subtitles and there are more than one blank line between title and subtitle. According to the flowchart of the Citing Article Template, some subtitles will be missing. The second lowest extraction percentage is author address. This is so as some author's address in these electronic journals was hyper-linked to other locations such as the author's own home page so that address information is missing. However, taken as a whole, the efficiency of the Citing Article Template to extract information is very promising.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cited article template</head><p>Figure <ref type="figure">8</ref> summarizes the results of evaluation for the cited article templates. There are much more variations in these templates in contrast to the Citing Article Template. It is was found that in some electronic journal articles, more than one form of citation may have been used in one same article. Thus, there is a need for more templates to cope with these larger variations. Even with these templates, many exceptions cannot be considered:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">0% 10% 20% 30% 40% 50% 60% 70% 80% 90% 100%</formula><p>conference citation can be subsequently followed by a book citation, or a conference citation followed by an hyperlink pointing to the electronic source.</p><p>• In the 'Journal Info' slot, information about the journa l such as the volume, issue, date, page number and so on, are not always consistent and can cause exceptions. For example, 'Wired 3.07' (What does '3.07' imply?), 'Online, 20(4), <ref type="bibr">12-14, 15-18, 20-21'</ref> (Is this some form of multiple page numbers?), and so on.</p><p>• There are also special exceptions that can cause the cited article templates to fail.</p><p>Examples of such text include: 'Plato, The Republic (Gyges's Ring is in Book II).', 'Carina Chocano, "Don't Worry, Be Hacky," Salon.', 'Strong pound hits Reed Elsevier, Bookseller, 15 August 1997, 8.'. Other special exceptions include those of personal communications and those that lack important parts (like author name, book name and so on) in cited articles. Despite these exceptions, the overall result of the evalua tion is quite satisfactory. Exceptions noted will provide additional information to improve these templates in future. Overall, this study has demonstrated the efficiency of template mining techniques in extraction of citing and cited reference information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Information extraction through template mining has widely been viewed as being closely related to NLP. In the absence of NLP capabilities, there is a need to select relevant information using one or more predictive and approximation methods. These could include statistical approaches, pattern matching, spatial positioning approach, and so on. The use of these methods is akin to obtaining some clues regarding certain words and their positions.</p><p>The proposed templates are initial prototypes that require further work in order to achieve more satisfactory results. For example, some authors put notes and references together, which means that they not only cite the articles but also add some notes to each cited article. This makes the automatic extraction of these citation formats even more complicated and challenging. Another example could be the diverse conference citation formats, electronic resource formats and other miscellaneous formats. In this study, we ignored the footnotes appearing in the text. All these difficulties and diversities point out the needs for future studies. In addition, as these templates are derived for a sample subset of available publications, further work needs to be carried out to gauge the applicability and effectiveness of the proposed templates on these other publications.</p><p>It is acknowledged that the templates' ability to recognise the citation components will be determined by the sequence and matching process found in these articles, else the extraction procedure will not reach the desired level of success. If the approach for the IE application is to be made sequence-free, then additional advanced techniques (e.g. those used in NLP processing) or heuristics will be needed to be incorporated in the approach. There are also some possibilities to improve the validity and reliability of the system. For example, building up the supporting databases, such as journal name database, publisher database, country database, and so on, will help the system improve the results.. However, further research needs to be conducted for identifying the best possible approach that is both technically and economically feasible.</p><p>Although the general patterns of citation and citing articles appear to be quite simple, this study has revealed that many irregularities exist in these citations, thereby adding on to the difficulty of successful template mining. It has been observed that the frequency of irregularities is much higher in e-journals than in print journals. In an e-journal, some authors have, even in the same article, used different ways to define the references. The reason for this could be that there are more vigorous checks in the print form by the editors and publishers in order to ensure adherence to house styles. In an e-journal, emphasis on such checks could be diluted in an attempt to bring out an online version in a shorter time, or that there is simply a lack of resource committed for online publications.</p><p>Irregularities make it difficult to detect clues to generalize the citing templates. There could be several ways to sort out these irregularities and to ensure standard style: to standardize the publishing process, to normalize different miscellaneous editorial rules and so on. One proposal by Chowdhury <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> is highly recommendable here. He proposed to prepare templates for each type of citation and to make them available online. Authors can download and make use of these templates for preparing the list of references and the whole style of article. This will ensure standard citation styles and eventually the whole structure of articles can be standardized, thereby facilitating the use of template mining with minimal or non-existent irregularities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p>This study has shown the potential of template mining to automatically create citation databases. Up to this moment in time, citation databases have largely been manually created. This is both time consuming, laborious, and prone to errors. The major hurdles to successful template mining are the irregularities that exist among the citations and the inconsistent styles among journals, especially in ejournals. Standardisation is clearly a potential option to allow automation. The proposed templates can form the initial steps in deriving these standard templates for the future.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><figDesc>The parallel publishing journal sample includes Journal of the American Society for Information, Science, Journal of Documentation, Journal of Information Science, Journal of Librarianship and Information Science, Program, Asian Libraries. The e-journal sample includes D -Lib magazine, Journal of electronic publishing, Katharine Sharp R eview, Journal of Library Services for Distance Education, Journal of Information, Law and Technology, First Monday.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 7 .Figure 7</head><label>77</label><figDesc>Figure 7. Distribution of information extraction from each unit in citing articles</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>','; '.'; space; line break; blank line; Author name (one line or several lines) a+ +a, c.+c.+ +a, a+ +c.+ +a ','; '&amp;'; 'and'; Line break; blank line;</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Among the various reference patterns, we generalized three cited article templates. Cited Article Template 1 is used for the reference beginning with cited author surname, Cited Article Template 2 is appropriate for the reference beginning with cited author forename, while Cited Article Template 3 is appropriate for the electronic references. These are shown in Figures <ref type="figure">4 to 6</ref> respectively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>System Evaluation</head><p>An evaluation was carried out to study the effectiveness of these templates as a means of extracting information from new articles. 34 new articles were collected from the same journal sample as the corpus of test data. Each article was analyzed manually and information for the templates was also manually filled in.  • In the 'Author Name' slot, Chinese authors can pose an exception since their surname does not necessarily appear last in the author name (e.g. 'Bonnie Cheuk Wai-yi', ' Gong Yitai'). Additionally, some articles do not contain the author's information. This will cause all subsequent information to be wrongly filled according to the flowchart.</p><p>• In the 'Title' slot, punctuation is the main reason that can cause exceptions. For exa mple, in the title 'Information distributions, Part II: Resilience to ambiguity', the comma will separate the whole title into two parts, the first part been tagged to the 'Title' slot and the other tagged to 'Book or other title' Subsequent information of this cited article will also go to the wrong slots. Such forms of exceptions are very common in 'Book or other title', 'Publisher', 'Book or other Info' and 'Journal Name' slot. 'Book or other Info' slot is the one with the lowest extraction percentage. This slot not only includes book information but conference, report and other types of information that are not easily locatable or definable due to the wide variety of formats adopted by authors. Additionally, a number of citations contain more than one type of reference information. For example, a</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
